# Justin Sanders

# Full Stack Developer

## Personal Info

Address

2970 North Sheridan Rd. Chicago, Illinois

Phone

331-201-8648

**Email** 

blitz1616@hotmail.com

Website

justinsanders.io

Github

https://github.com/SandersJ16 https://github.com/SandersJ16-Pro

#### LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/justinsanderscodemastersupreme/

## Skills

Dynamically/Weakly Typed Languages (PHP, Python, Ruby)

Expert

Statically/Strongly Typed Languages (Java, C#, VB, C)

**Proficient** 

Linux and Bash

Advanced

Front-End Technologies (HTML, CSS, JS, Ajax, SCSS, ReactJS, etc.)

Advanced

Teamwork

**Problem Solving** 

# **Summary**

Full stack software developer with 3+ year professional experience and 12+ years personal experience. I have a genuine passion for coding and often work on my own projects in my spare time outside of work. I currently work on a small team managing multiple large-scale web applications on multiple frameworks and platforms for hundreds of universities and corporate clients. Working on a small team has made me a strong team player and given me a chance to work on every aspect of a client facing commercial software.

# **Experience**

2015 - Present

# Software Engineer Wellspring Worldwide

- Functioning within a team performing agile development and collaborating with other teams to create quality commercial web applications.
- Several recently accomplished projects/achievements include:
  - Integration of our newly acquired document/start-up search engine and our tech scout/venture capital software to allow imports from one to the other
  - Major refactor of our dashboard system to be more flexible and easily extensible allowing for easier creation of new dashboard widgets
  - Worked with ops team in defining our software's server requirements and setup in puppet, this allowed us to migrate all of our servers to AWS
  - Created an easily deployable development environment using docker and docker-compose for a newly acquired product allowing new developers to quickly set up a local environment
  - Re-implemented a system wide search using angular2 and solr increasing aesthetics and page speed by over 80%
- Creating new features, adding functionality to existing features and refactoring legacy code for multiple large-scale web applications, in a variety of frameworks and languages (including multiple PHP Frameworks, Ruby on Rails, Django and others).
- Front-end development using a variety of technologies (ReactJS, erb, bootstrap, custom JS frameworks, Django Templates, React-Router, Angular2)
- Creation of automation for deployment, testing and other processes for our products using Jenkins, Django and other tools
- Creation of internal tooling for increased team and company productivity, using vagrant, docker, git hooks, other scripts, etc.
- Training new developers in coding practices, new software languages, our application stacks and our development life-cycle
- SQL Database (MySQL, Postgres) management and integration with software products
- Working directly with client's IT teams to integrate SAML authentication with our systems
- Integration with Project Managers and Client Services in solving client concerns and planning/creating new software features

# Justin Sanders

# Full Stack Developer

## Personal Info

Address

2970 North Sheridan Rd. Chicago, Illinois

Phone

331-201-8648

**Email** 

blitz1616@hotmail.com

Website

justinsanders.io

Github

https://github.com/SandersJ16 https://github.com/SandersJ16-Pro

#### LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/justinsandersc odemastersupreme/

## Skills

Dynamically/Weakly Typed Languages (PHP, Python, Ruby)

Expert

Statically/Strongly Typed Languages (Java, C#, VB, C)

**Proficient** 

Linux and Bash

Advanced

Front-End Technologies (HTML, CSS, JS, Ajax, SCSS, ReactJS, etc.)

Advanced

Teamwork

**Problem Solving** 

# **Experience**

2013 – 2014 (Full time summer, part time during school)

Applications UI Developer (Intern)

#### **Stone River Insurance Solutions**

- Creation User interface forms for a desktop application
- Using custom C++ framework for development of User Forms from XML templates
- Modifying exiting framework to add new required functionality
- Using Visual Basic 6 for data retrieval and manipulation for UI
- Worked with QA testers, project managers and translators to ensure creation of a quality product
- Database management using MS Access

### **Education**

2012 - 2015

University of Windsor (Honours Bachelor of Computer Science)

- Assisted professor with his research into using natural language for querying data
- Did tutoring in Physics and Math
- Honed my skills in programming and expanded my knowledge of software in many areas

# **Other Skills**

- Strong Decision Maker
- Vagrant, Puppet and Docker
- Basic Apache
- Agile Methodology
- Git and Github/Bitbucket
- Single Page Applications

- Postgres and MySQL
- Windows, Mac and Linux Operating Systems
- Jenkins
- SAML Integrations
- Software Architecture
- Solr